Woody Allen Papers, 1955-2012: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 6: Additions, 1964 April 9-2004 May 26; 10.0 boxes
  - Subseries 6A: Film and Theater Scripts, 1968-2004 May 26; 8.0 boxes
    - September (1987 film), 1986; 1.0 item (Folder 4)
      TMs bound copy of screenplay, 74 pp.
    - Shadows and Fog (1992 film), 1990; 1.0 item (Folder 5)
      TMs bound copy of screenplay, 102 pp.
    - Sleeper (1973 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 6)
      TMs of original film script by Allen and Marshall Brickman (Xerox), 114 pp.
    - Sleeper (1973 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 7)
      TMs of screenplay, 107 pp.
    - Stardust Memories (1980 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 8)
      TMs bound copy of screenplay, 95 pp.
    - Sweet and Lowdown (1999 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 1)
      TMs bound copy of original screenplay, 108 pp., titled "The Jazz Baby" on the front cover
    - Take the Money and Run (1969 film), 1968; 1.0 item (Folder 2)
      TMs of original screenplay by Allen and Mickey Rose, 122 pp.
    - Zelig (1983 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 3)
      TMs bound copy of film script (no. 4), 91 pp., titled "Summer Two" on the front cover and title page.
    - Zelig (1983 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 4)
      TMs bound copy of film script (no. 22), 91 pp., titled "Summer Two" on the front cover and title page as well as "Zelig" written on the title page.
    - Zelig (1983 film), undated; 1.0 item (Folder 5)
      TMs bound copy of film script, 91 pp., titled "Summer Two" on the front cover and title page.
  - Subseries 6B: Video Cassettes and LP Records, 1964 April 9-1987 December 13; 2.0 boxes
    This subseries contains magnetic media: video cassette tapes (nine in 3/4 inch format and four in VHS format) and two 33 long play (LP) vinyl records.
    - Video Cassette Recordings, 1969-1987 December 13; 2.0 boxes (1 partial)
      - "Cine-Regards", undated; 1.0 item
        Interview of Woody Allen with French subtitles
      - "The Great Standups: Sixty Years of Laughter", 1984; 1.0 item
      - Woody Allen Act in "Hollywood: The Gift of Laughter", undated; 1.0 item
      - Woody Allen: "Men in Crisis", undated; 1.0 item
      - Woody Allen Standup: "Moose Routine", 1984 April 24; 1.0 item
        From a Granada TV mid-1960's recording
      - Love and Death (Part 1), undated; 1.0 item
        Labeled "Love and Death" on the box and "Bananas" on the tape.
      - Bananas (Part 1), undated; 1.0 item
      - Bananas (Part 2), undated; 1.0 item
      - Woody Allen: "Salute to Sullivan", undated; 1.0 item
      - Woody Allen Feature and Sitcom, 1976; 1.0 item
      - "Woody Allen Special" (VHS), 1969; 1.0 item
      - The McNeil/Lehrer Report Re: Film Colorization (VHS), 1986; 1.0 item
      - Jean-Luc Godard: "Meetin' Woody Allen" interview (VHS), 1986 May; 1.0 item
      - "60 Minutes" interview (VHS), 1987 December 13; 1.0 item
    - 33 1/3 LP Recordings, 1964 April 9; portion of 1 box
      - "Woody Allen", undated; 1.0 item
        Side 1: The Moose, The Kidnapping, Superman, Science Fiction Movie, Eggs Benedict, Footnote; Side 2: What's New Pussycat, Reminiscences, Swedish Movie, Taking A Shower (A Pantomime), The Lost Generation.
      - "Woody Allen at Mr. Kelly's", 1964 April 9; 1.0 item
- Series 7: Additions, 2006-2007; 2.0 boxes 2 boxes
  This series contains galley proofs of Allen's 2007 books, Mere Anarchy and The Insanity Defense, with a few autograph corrections by the author. Additions made in 2008.
  - The Insanity Defense (2007 book), 6.0 boxes
    - Miscellaneous page proofs, 2007 June; 1.0 folder (Folder 1)
      TMs with autograph corrections, unpaged
    - Page proofs - 2nd pass, 2007 March; 1.0 folder (Folder 2)
      TMs, 344 pp.
    - Rough page proofs - Master Set, 2007 February; 1.0 folder (Folder 3)
      TMs with autograph corrections, 344 pp.
    - Page proofs for layout, 2007; 1.0 folder (Folder 4)
      TMs with autograph corrections, 11 pp.
    - Page proofs - Setting Copy with printer's marks, 2007; 1.0 folder (Folder 5)
      TMs with autograph corrections, 336 pp.
  - Mere Anarchy (2007 book), 6.0 boxes
    - Miscellaneous page proofs, 2007 February-May; 1.0 folder (Folder 1)
      TMs with autograph corrections
    - Page proofs, 2007 January 25; 1.0 folder (Folder 2)
      TMs, 168 pp.
    - Rough page proofs - Master Set, 2006 November 10; 1.0 folder (Folder 3)
      TMs with autograph corrections, 168 pp.
    - Page proofs for layout, undated; 1.0 folder (Folder 4)
      TMs, 11 pp.
    - Page proofs with autograph corrections by Allen and publisher corrections, undated; 1.0 folder (Folder 5)
      TMs with autograph corrections, 104 pp.
- Series 8: Additions, 2007-2012; 3 boxes
  Consists of four film scripts, including Midnight in Paris and To Rome with Love; a stage play entitled Honeymoon Motel; and eleven articles and short stories. Additions made in May 2012.
  - Subseries 8A: Screenplays, 2007-2011; 2 boxes
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    Consists of drafts of screenplays and promotional materials.
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Rough First Draft, circa 2009 January 12; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      TMs with autograph edits. Envelope reads: "Rough first draft of Midnight in Paris re-written for Woody to play lead."
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Later Draft, circa 2009 January; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      TMs with autograph edits. Envelope reads: "Numbered pages may be off a bit but script is in order + numbers in normal order."
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Revision Copy, 2010 January 12; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      TMs with autograph edits.
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Later Version, 2010 January 20; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      TMs with autograph edits. Envelope reads: "Some later version of Midnight in Paris (possibly the Hollywood writer version)"
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Latest Draft, 2010 February 11; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Paste-up TMs with autograph edits. Envelope reads: "Copy of Midnight in Paris - rough - for archive."
    - Screenplays: Midnight in Paris (2011) Draft Promotional Images and Text, circa 2010; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Screenplays: To Rome with Love (The Bop Decameron) (2012) Manuscript Draft, circa 2011; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      AMss.
    - Screenplays: To Rome with Love (The Bop Decameron) (2012) Typed Draft, circa 2011; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Screenplays: Vicky Cristina Barcelona (2008) Typed Draft, 2007 January 19; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Screenplays: Vicky Cristina Barcelona (2008) Typed Draft, 2007 March 9; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Screenplays: You Will Meet a Tall Dark Stranger (2010) Early Draft and Notes, 2007-2009; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      AMss and TMs with autograph edits, paste-ups.
    - Screenplays: You Will Meet a Tall Dark Stranger (2010) Draft, 2007-2009; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      TMs with autograph edits, paste-ups.
    - Screenplays: You Will Meet a Tall Dark Stranger (2010) Photocopied Draft, 2007-2009; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Color photocopies of a later draft, combining different TMss with autograph edits.
  - Subseries 8B: Stage Play, 2010-2011; 1 box
    This subseries is arranged in two folders.
    Consists of one stage play.
    - Stage Play: Honeymoon Motel Manuscript Draft, 2010-2011; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      AMs.
    - Stage Play: Honeymoon Motel Typescript Draft, 2010-2011; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Subseries 8C: Short Stories and Articles, 2008-2012; 2 boxes
    Consists of short stories and articles written primarily for The New Yorker magazine. Includes some alternate titles on draft versions. Publication date is included when known.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "A Little Face Work Never Hurt", 2008; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      Six drafts. TMss with autograph edits. Appeared in the Fall 2008 issue of Zoetrope: All-Story.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Heavy Bread and Its Relation to the Unconscious", 2010; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      One TMs with autograph edits and one unmarked TMs. Appeared in the Summer 2010 issue of Zoetrope: All-Story.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Money Can Buy Happiness—As If", 2010-2011; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      Two drafts of "Money Can Buy Happiness—As If," which appeared in a January 2011 issue of The New Yorker. Alternate titles of drafts: "I Hear the Financial Crisis is Serious" (TMs with autograph edits) and "It's the Economy, Stupid" (TMs).
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Mr. De Mille, I'm Ready for my Hearse", undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      Multiple drafts. AMss and TMss with autograph edits. One unmarked TMs.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Mug Hurled at Mona Lisa", circa 2009; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      Three drafts. AMs and TMs with autograph edits.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Not a Creature was Stirring", 2012 April 19; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      TMs. Appeared in a May 2012 edition of The New Yorker.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Over, Around, and Through, Your Highness", 2008; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      One AMs and five TMss with autograph edits. Appeared in a May 2008 edition of the The New Yorker.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Udder Madness", 2009-2010; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      Four drafts of "Udder Madness" which appeared in a January 2010 edition of The New Yorker. All TMss with autograph edits.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Tails of Manhattan", 2009; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Three drafts. AMs and two TMss. Appeared in a March 2009 edition of The New Yorker.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Think Hard, It'll Come to You", 2008 July 22; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      Four drafts. Three TMs with autograph edits, one unmarked TMs. Appeared in a November 2008 edition of The New Yorker.
    - Short Stories and Articles: "Will the Real Avatar Please Stand Up?", 2010 April 23; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      Three drafts of "Will the Real Avatar Please Stand Up?" which appeared in a May 2010 issue of The New Yorker. Alternate title: "Beatty Shouts." TMss with autograph edits.
  - Subseries 8D: The New Yorker Manuscripts, 2007-2012; 1 folder
    This subseries is arranged in one folder.
    Consists of miscellaneous hand-written manuscript material from a legal pad. Possibly contains notes relating to other works within Series 8.
    - The New Yorker Manuscripts, 2007-2012; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      Manuscript note on original envelope reads: "New Yorker Material - Some published eventually, some not." Some identifiable drafts were removed from this material and placed with appropriate files in Subseries 8C: Short Stories and Articles.
- March 2014 Accession, 2009-2014; 1.4 linear feet 2 boxes
  Contains drafts of stage plays, screenplays, and short prose pieces in various stages of conception and production, including scripts for Blue Jasmine, Magic in the Moonlight, and Irrational Man. Also includes fragments and abandoned drafts.
  Arranged by genre and title of the work.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Contains first autograph and typed drafts with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    Contains a partial early typed draft with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    Contains an early (yellow) draft with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), 2012 March 9-14; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    First production script (white and yellow) with revised pages and typed and autograph revisions.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), 2012 May 31; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    Subsequent production script (white and yellow) with revised pages and typed and autograph revisions.
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), 2012 June 5; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Blue Jasmine (Screenplay), undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    White draft with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Magic In the Moonlight (Screenplay), 2013; portion of 1 folder (Folder 8)
    First, autograph draft.
  - Magic In the Moonlight (Screenplay), undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 9)
    Contains early (yellow) autograph and typed draft fragments with autograph revisions.
  - Magic In the Moonlight (Screenplay), undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 10)
    Early (yellow) draft with autograph and typed revisions.
  - Magic In the Moonlight (Screenplay), 2013 March 20; portion of 1 folder (Folder 11)
    Early (yellow/white) with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Magic In the Moonlight (Screenplay), 2013 June 13; portion of 1 folder (Folder 12)
    Shooting script.
  - Midnight in Paris (Screenplay), undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    Early draft with autograph revisions and revised pages/partial pages.
  - Whatever Works (Screenplay), 2008; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    Draft with autograph revisions and revised pages/partial pages.
  - Vicky Cristina Barcelona (Screenplay), 2007; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    Autograph draft.
  - You Will Meet a Tall, Dark Stranger (Screenplay), 2009; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    Early draft with autograph revisions.
  - A Second Hand Memory (Stageplay), 2004; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    Final draft. Clean copy. Premiered 2004/11/22 at the Atlantic Theater Company.
  - Bullets over Broadway (Musical), 2013; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    Draft with autograph and typed revisions based on the movie production script. Includes autograph song list.
  - A Prestige Address, 2012; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Read at Readers and Writers series at Weill Cornell Medical College, April 9, 2013.
  - Blotnick's Insight, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    Includes autograph draft and typed drafts with autograph revisions.
  - For Sale: Ten Room Apartment--Humiliation Included, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    Includes autograph draft, typed drafts with autograph revisions, and final draft with autograph revisions.
  - Hypochondria: An Inside Look (Op-Ed), 2012; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    Includes autograph draft and several early drafts with autograph revisions. Published in The New York Times on January 12, 2013.
  - Melpomene--Help!, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Mr. De Mille, I'm Ready For My Hearse, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    Typed draft with typed and autograph revisions.
  - Not A Creature Was Stirring, 2012; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    Contains autograph draft and typed draft with autograph revisions. Published in the Shouts & Murmurs column of the New Yorker on March 28, 2012.
  - Now, Where Did I Leave That Oxygen Tank?, 2013; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    Includes autograph draft and early drafts as well as a clean copy of the final draft. Published in The New Yorker on August 5, 2013.
  - On the Red Carpet, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    Includes research materials, autograph notes, early drafts with autograph revisions, and clean copy of final draft.
  - Rememberant By a Nose, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    Includes autograph draft and early through final drafts with autograph revisions.
  - Tails of Manhattan, 2009; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    Clean copy. Published in the Shouts & Murmus column of The New Yorker on March 30, 2009.
  - The One That Got Away--Me, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Wake Me When It's Over, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    Includes autograph draft and several early drafts with autograph revisions.
  - Irrational Man, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    Includes autograph draft and typed draft with autograph corrections.
  - Unidentified Stage Play Draft, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    Includes autograph and typed early drafts of single scenes.
  - Unidentified Stage Play Draft, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    Contains autograph draft of the beginning of a scene. The dialog concerns one of the characters, a playwright, casting one of the other characters for a role in a play within the play.
  - Unidentified Film Scene Draft, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 17)
    Autograph draft of a film scene set during a presidential campaign.
  - Unidentified Film Scene Draft, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 18)
    Autograph draft of a film scene in which a character orders a hit on his wife.
  - Unidentified Short Fiction/Satire Drafts, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 19)
    Includes autograph drafts of short pieces based on news clippings.
- September 2014 Accession, 1995-2005; 6 boxes
  Includes a group of international press clippings and publicity materials, regarding many of Allen's films from 1995 to 2005, including Mighty Aphrodite, Deconstructing Harry, Wild Man Blues, Sweet and Lowdown, Celebrity, Small Time Crooks, The Curse of the Jade Scorpion, Hollywood Ending, Anything Else, and Melinda and Melinda. Materials include newspaper clippings and photocopies of articles on actors and film reviews, production information and notes, printed and recorded interviews, and occasional photographic materials. Some materials also relate to press for other events, including the Venice Film Festival and Allen's tours with his jazz band in the early 2000s.
  Original order was maintained, which follows a rough chronological order.
  - Mighty Aphrodite, 1995 December; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    Schedule for International Press, newspaper clipping, and list of completed interviews.
  - Deconstructing Harry, 1997 December-1998 March; 5 folders (Folder 2-6)
    International Press Junket, production information and notes, and reviews and clippings.
  - Wild Man Blues, 1998 February-April; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
    Photographs, production notes, reviews, interviews.
  - Various Cassettes of TV Interviews and Clips of Sweet and Lowdown, 1999-2001; 4 folders (Folder 9-12)
    11 cassettes, 3 of which are unlabelled, 4 are of Sweet and Lowdown, and 4 are of TV interviews.
  - "The New York Knicks", 2002 January; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Celebrity, 1998 May-1999 June; 7 folders (Folder 14-20)
    Photographs, production notes, and reviews.
  - Small Time Crooks, 2000-2001; 6 folders (Folder 1-6)
    Reviews, schedules of completed interviews, 2 cassettes of interviews, 1 CD of photographs, photographic slides, and production notes.
  - Venice Film Festival, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
    Materials related to The Curse of the Jade Scorpian and Sweet and Lowdown.
  - Samantha Morton Oscar Campaign, 2000; 3 folders (Folder 9-11)
    Press clippings
  - Interviews, 2000-2002; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    Interviews with Woody Allen, Samantha Morton, and Mia Farrow.
  - Sweet and Lowdown, 1999-2000; 3 folders (Folder 13-15)
    Public relations materials, lists of interviews, production notes.
  - Sweet and Lowdown, 1999-2000; 10 folders (Folder 1-10)
    Photographs and press cuttings.
  - The Curse of the Jade Scorpion, 2001; 4 folders (Folder 11-14)
    Photographs, lists of interviews, and press reviews.
  - The Curse of the Jade Scorpion, 2001; 6 folders (Folder 1-6)
    Press reviews.
  - Prince of Austrias Awards for the Arts, 2002; 3 folders (Folder 7-9)
  - Jazz Tour, 2002; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Hollywood Ending, Cannes Film Festival Opening Night, 2002; 13 folders (Folder 1-13)
    Photography, press reviews, and posters for film festival.
  - Anything Else, 2003; 2 folders (Folder 14-15)
    Photographs, reviews, production notes, and materials related to Venice Film Festival.
  - Red Cross Event, Monaco, 2004 July-August; 1 folder (Folder 16)
  - Jazz Band Tour, 2002-2004; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    CD of photos (2002) and press reviews (2004).
  - Melinda and Melinda Tour, 2004-2005; 2 folders (Folder 1-2)
    Production notes, reviews, tour schedules.
  - Various Audio and Video Cassettes, 1997-2002; 7 folders (Folder 3-9)
- 32101080816117 (Box 6)
- 32101080816075 (Box 1)
- 32101080816083 (Box 3)
- 32101080816109 (Box 5)
- 32101080816067 (Box 2)
- 32101080816091 (Box 4)
- 32101080816125 (Box 7)
- 32101080816133 (Box 8)
- 32101080816141 (Box 9)
- 32101080816158 (Box 10)
- 32101080816166 (Box 11)
- 32101080816174 (Box 12)
- 32101080816182 (Box 13)
- 32101080816190 (Box 14)
- 32101080816208 (Box 15)
- 32101080816216 (Box 16)
- 32101080816224 (Box 17)
- 32101037662465 (Box 18)
- 32101037662457 (Box 19)
- 32101037662432 (Box 20)
- 32101037662440 (Box 21)
- 32101037662416 (Box 22)
- 32101037662424 (Box 23)
- 32101037662408 (Box 24)
- 32101037662713 (Box 25)
- 32101037662705 (Box 26)
- 32101037662697 (Box 27)
- 32101037662689 (Box 28)
- 32101037662671 (Box 29)
- 32101037662663 (Box 30)
- 32101037662655 (Box 31)
- 32101037662648 (Box 32)
- 32101037662630 (Box 33)
- 32101037662960 (Box 34)
- 32101037662952 (Box 35)
- 32101037662945 (Box 36)
- 32101037662937 (Box 37)
- 32101037662929 (Box 38)
- 32101037662911 (Box 39)
- 32101037662903 (Box 40)
- 32101037662895 (Box 41)
- 32101037662887 (Box 42)
- 32101037663190 (Box 43)
- 32101037663786 (Box 44)
- 32101037663778 (Box 45)
- 32101080826256 (Box 46)
- 32101080826264 (Box 47)
- 32101080826272 (Box 48)
- 32101080516717 (Box 49)
- 32101080516709 (Box 50)
- 32101080517335 (Box 52)
- 32101080517327 (Box 53)
- 32101080517319 (Box 54)
- 32101080517301 (Box 55)
- 32101080517293 (Box 56)
- 32101080517285 (Box 57)